# Joo Heredia 13800 Newcastle Golf Club Rd Apt 228 Newcastle, WA 98509

Cell Number (972) 903-5950 E-mail: jooheredia@gmail.com

#### **Summary**

Achievement-oriented analyst skilled at recognizing and launching the steps needed to attain objectives seeks career opportunity with your organization. Offering diverse business and technical experience facilitating a broad range of company and customer initiatives: combines strong planning, organizational and communications skills with the ability to ensure smooth flow of daily operations within fast-paced and changing environment. Facilitate a team work environment to increase productivity and enhance employee morale.

#### **Professional Experience**

#### American Airlines - Fort Worth, TX 2018

#### AAdvantage Customer Specialist - Customer Insights and Loyalty (CI & L) Department

- Assist AAdvantage members maintain their accounts and support the marketing efforts of the Customer Insights & Loyalty team.
- Take ownership and demonstrate expertise of the AAdvantage product while providing the highest quality of customer service in each and every contact.
- Demonstrate above average communication skills and analytical abilities in order to research and respond to customer inquiries using AA Software and SABRE.

## **Verizon Wireless –** Southlake, TX 2011 - 2017 **Network Repair Bureau Technician**

- Responsible for analysis, resolution, and follow up of customer impacting events within the Verizon Wireless network.
- Comprehend architecture and overall system functionality of the voice and data network and apply towards troubleshooting network issue.
- Troubleshoot and resolve any and all service impairments related to roaming (domestic, international, and global), transport services (Telco and Long distance), network hardware and software faults (switch and cell site), translations, and voice/data network elements.
- Isolate and resolve wireless voice and data faults which include: correlating customer complaints with network element performance to resolve service impacting condition.
- Drive issues to resolution by engaging internal and external resources such as Switch
  Operations, Network Operations Center, System Performance, Maintenance Engineering(or any other network organization), as well as equipment vendors, service providers,
  and roaming partners.
- Provide accurate and timely documentation via Remedy of actions taken to inform other Network technicians of issues and resolutions.
- Trend the Remedy trouble ticketing queue to identify efficiencies.
- Reduce Average Customer Experience (ACE) time in resolving customer reported issues.

#### **Technician - Data Service Operations - Maintenance**

- Utilize multiple application including, Cisco ANA, IP Control, Service Director, HP Openview, Network Compliance Manager (NCM), and IP Solution Center (ISC), to troubleshoot, isolate, and restore network outages.
- Investigate, isolate, and restore all major, critical and catastrophic network events.
- Coordinate network data outages with responsible departments and/or Vendor to minimize downtime.
- Work with region, engineering, DSO-Implementation on supporting change controls, failover testing, and verification of Pre and Post testing.
- Operate and maintaining Juniper M480, M320, SRX, Crossbeam IDS, Big IP F5 Load balancers, Cisco routers 12K,10K,7500,7300,3800, CRS, Switches, 6500.
- Experience hands-on working knowledge and understanding of multiple network technologies including MPLS, BGP, OSPF, ATM, QOS, from working with region, vendors and engineering.
- Provide Second tier technical support to the National Network Operations and Regional Operations organizations
- Support, identify, and isolate, large network outage on multiple VZW network (WDN, EDN, OTN, IT, OBM)
- Troubleshoot OSI layer 1, 2, and 3 issue, including OSPF, BGP, ATM, Firewall, DS0 through OC-48 circuits
- Support VZW Corporate stores on Layer 1 (fiber) and Layer 2 (ATM) using Cisco 8850 & 8950 and Nortel Passport.
- Work with regional switches on Transport and Starent PDSN/HA issues.
- Interface with equipment vendors for troubleshooting, RCA, and RMA.
- Support and interface with Data Service Operations and Maintenance Engineering on Outages and Network Capacity issues.

## **ATI Enterprises, Inc. –** North Richland Hills, TX 2010 - 2011 **Corporate Assistant Registrar**

- Ensure compliance with administrative policies and procedures are maintained in accordance with ATI Enterprises and accreditation standards.
- Assist with all training of campus level registrars, auditing, creating schedules and school start calendars, student registration and records.

## **ITT Corporation, Systems Division –** Bagram, Afghanistan 2008 – 2010 **Systems Administrator**

- Responsible for operations, administration and maintenance (OA&M) of an Enterpriseclass Army System of both NIPR (Non-Secure Internet Protocol Router Network) and SIPR (Secret Internet Protocol Router Network) supporting over 400 users and five remote sites.
- Performed routine system backups, account creation in Active Directory and Exchange 2003, hardware/software installation and upgrades.
- Troubleshot server, user and network issues related to Microsoft Windows 2003 Server operating environment, as well as server based applications.
- Verified that Windows Server Update Services was synchronizing with upstream server.

- Ran Retina Network Security Scanner to check for infected computers and remediated virus/malware.
- Verified that Symantec server was pulling updates on virus definitions and were not over a week old.
- Responsible for Exchange 2003 Server Maintenance: verified no messages are holding
  in the exchange Queue, cleaned out unlinked accounts from exchange if any exist,
  made sure all exchange stores are mounted and working, troubleshot message routing
  or delivery issues.
- Maintained Systems Availability and performed regular maintenance on equipments.
- Verified backups on servers were successful or troubleshot to repair; checked every job task list and made sure everything ran successfully, checked for failure check error message.

### **Southwest Airlines –** Dallas, TX 2007 – 2008 **Network Operations Specialist**

- Provided second tier network monitoring, support, and maintenance of Southwest Airlines network infrastructure to include over 2800 Cisco devices across the United States.
- Completed service request for network connectivity of UNIX and Windows environments.
- Ran and terminated Ethernet and Fiber Optic cable to Cisco devices within the Data Center, provisioned router and switch ports.
- Tracked and escalated network outages and fault conditions utilizing Remedy ticketing system to ensure proper resolution for service availability.
- Physically installed routers and switches connecting to the fiber and copper network.
- Troubleshot WAN connectivity, bandwidth utilization, and routing issues.
- Performed Cisco IOS upgrades on multiple routers and switches within the network.

## **Verizon Wireless –** Southlake, TX 2002 – 2007 **Network Operation Center Technician**

- Monitored Verizon Wireless cellular and data network from a centralized Network Operations Center (NOC).
- Responsible for troubleshooting circuit facilities, TCP/IP network issues, Nortel 10k passport, Cisco 3845, 6500 router and switch configurations, EVDO, CDMA and analog base stations to ensure high availability and attainment of service levels.
- Performed remote testing and performance analysis of facilities to include: T1 and frame-relay circuits; digital cross-connect systems, CSU's, Lucent 5ESS/ECP, Nortel MTX/BSSM, and Motorola CBSC/EMX/OMCDO.
- Provided 2<sup>nd</sup> Tier troubleshooting support to NOC technicians regarding CISCO routers/ switches, Lucent 5eSS/ECP, Nortel MTX/BSSM, and Motorola CBSC/EMX/OMCDO
- Responsible for assigning NOC Technicians geographical market assignments on a weekly basis.
- Provided guidance to all NOC Technicians, ensuring they follow NOC procedures.

WebLink Wireless, Inc. - Dallas, TX1999 - 2002 Systems Engineering, Technical Services Technician III

- Responsible for identifying, researching and documenting every component of the Web-Link Wireless Messaging Network including terminals (switches), routers, hubs, encoders, frame relay circuits, telco circuits, and transmitters.
- Utilized documentation software such as NetViz and Visio to create data rich embedded multi-layered diagrams and illustrations.
- Provided comprehensive detailed drawings of network equipment including specific portto-port interconnections.
- Created and wrote Standard Operating Procedures for WebLink Wireless Network implementation.
- Commissioned new transmitter sites as well as site moves, ensured all sites are programmed correctly and are fully functional.

#### **EDUCATION / CERTIFICATION**

Bachelor of Journalism/Public Affair University of Texas at Austin

December 1995

CompTIA Network+ CompTIA Security+ CompTIA Linux+ May 2008 September 2008 October 2017